Hello, Mr Herriot.
你好，赫里奥特先生。
Hello, Tom. Good of you to
help out the Dalbys like this.
你好，汤姆。你能
像这样帮助达尔比一家，真是太好了。
They've always been good
friends of my grandparents.
他们一直是
我祖父母的好朋友。
Mrs Dalby's up in t' field.
I'll take you.
达尔比夫人在田野里。
我带你去。
Thanks, Tom.
谢谢，汤姆。
Morning, Mr Herriot.
早上好，赫里奥特先生。
Thanks for coming out to see us.
谢谢你出来见我们。
And thank you for
being there yesterday.
谢谢你
昨天在场。
Billy was a good man.
比利是个好人。
I wanted to pay my respects.
我想表达我的敬意。
Their breathing don't
sound right, Mr Herriot.
他们的呼吸
听起来不太对劲，赫里奥特先生。
They were really fit when they
turned out earlier this month.
当他们
本月早些时候出现时，他们真的很健康。
Then, well...
那么，嗯...
Let's have a look, then, shall we?
那我们来看看好吗？
The stirks have got husk, I'm afraid.
马镫有壳了，恐怕。
For an older cow
this may not be our problem
对于一头老母牛，
这可能不是我们的问题
but as they are still so young...
但因为他们还那么年轻......
Aye, and what is husk, exactly?
是的，什么是外壳？
Well, it's a parasite.
嗯，是寄生虫。
A tiny worm which infests
the bronchial tubes
一种感染
支气管的小蠕虫
and sets up bronchitis.
并引发支气管炎。
The larvae climb up the blades of grass
幼虫爬上草叶
and the cattle eat them as they graze.
牛在吃草时吃掉它们。
Some pastures are badly
affected with it.
一些牧场受到严重
影响。
I'm sorry but they're pretty bad,
Mrs Dalby.
对不起，他们很糟糕，
达尔比夫人。
A mild attack isn't so bad
轻微的攻击并没有那么糟糕
if you can get them
off the grass right away
如果你能
马上把它们从草地上弄下来
but this has gone
a long way beyond that.
但这
远远不止于此。
What can we do about it, Mr Herriot?
我们能做些什么，赫里奥特先生？
For a start, we can get them
all inside immediately.
首先，我们可以
立即将它们全部放入。
Every mouthful of this grass
is adding to the worm burden.
每一口这种草
都增加了蠕虫的负担。
Right you are, Mr Herriot.
你说得对，赫里奥特先生。
Can I... tempt you with
the last egg, Mrs H?
我可以……用
最后一个鸡蛋诱惑你吗，H 夫人？
No thanks.
不，谢谢。
Seems a shame to waste it.
浪费它似乎很可惜。
I thought you'd be joining your friends
我以为你会加入你的朋友
down in London for the cricket.
在伦敦打板球。
Yes, I thought so too
是的，我也是这么想的
but unfortunately tickets require
money and money requires wages,
但不幸的是门票需要
钱，钱需要工资，
neither of which I possess.
这两个我都不拥有。
So instead, my plan is
three uninterrupted days
所以相反，我的计划是
三天不间断
with my feet up, the radio on
and a lovely, cool glass of...
抬起脚，打开收音机
，喝一杯可爱、凉爽的...
Well, it took all of five hours
嗯，花了五个小时
but Gladys produced
a whopping 18 piglets.
但是格拉迪斯生产
了多达 18 头小猪。
Darrowby record, I believe.
达罗比记录，我相信。
Smells like one, too.
闻起来也很像。
They need cleaning. Get them off.
他们需要清洁。把他们弄下来。
Any chance of some breakfast?
有机会吃早餐吗？
I can make you a bacon sandwich.
And those.
我可以给你做一个培根三明治。
以及那些。
Think I've had enough pig
for one day. Got any eggs?
想想我已经吃够
了一天的猪了。有鸡蛋吗？
You can have the rest
of this one if you like.
如果你愿意，你可以拥有剩下的。
So I'm out working my trousers off
所以我要脱掉裤子
while you're lazing around stuffing
your face with my hard-earned eggs?
当你懒洋洋地
用我辛苦赚来的鸡蛋塞满你的脸时？
Such is life, big brother.
Such is life.
这就是生活，大哥。
这就是人生。
Go and get changed.
I'll make you some toast.
去换衣服。
我给你做些吐司。
You really didn't need to go
to all this trouble. Nonsense.
你真的没有必要
遇到这些麻烦。废话。
I hope that tea isn't too
strong for you. It's perfect.
我希望茶
对你来说不是太浓。这是完美的。
Thank you, Mrs Dalby.
谢谢你，达尔比夫人。
I'll be back up tomorrow
to check on the stirks.
明天我会回来
检查马鞭。
Meanwhile, it's very important
that you keep them inside.
同时，
将它们留在里面非常重要。
Oh. But they'll need feeding.
哦。但他们需要喂食。
Well, at this point,
那么，在这一点上，
I would start by giving
them the best possible food -
我会先给
他们最好的食物——
good hay and high-protein cake.
好干草和高蛋白蛋糕。
Cake?
蛋糕？
That's expensive stuff, isn't it?
那是很贵的东西，不是吗？
And if we give them the hay now,
we'll need to buy more for winter.
如果我们现在给他们干草，
我们将需要购买更多的干草过冬。
I know but a good diet is
our best hope at this stage.
我知道，但
在这个阶段，良好的饮食是我们最大的希望。
And they can't go out to
feed on the grass ever?
他们不能出去
吃草吗？
No. I'm sorry, not on those fields.
不，对不起，不在那些领域。
If it was a mild attack,
you could have turned them out
如果这是一次轻微的攻击，
你可以把它们赶出去
after the dew had left in the mornings
在早晨露水离开之后
but that's not the case here.
但这里的情况并非如此。
Right.
对。
Well, thank you, Mr Herriot.
We know where we are anyway.
嗯，谢谢你，赫里奥特先生。
无论如何，我们知道我们在哪里。
Billy, love, why don't you take your
brother outside for a kickaround?
比利，亲爱的，你为什么不带你
弟弟出去玩玩呢？
Have we got a young
Gordon Hodgson in the making?
我们有一个年轻的
戈登霍奇森吗？
He's my favourite player.
他是我最喜欢的球员。
Good choice.
好的选择。
Go on, Billy, love.
继续，比利，亲爱的。
Oi, you.
Excuse me.
打扰一下。
Come on.
来吧。
So cheeky.
好厚脸皮
Do you think we can save them?
你觉得我们能救他们吗？
Well... we can always hope.
嗯……我们总是可以希望的。
Funny.
有趣的。
That's what my Billy
always used to say.
这就是我的比利
经常说的话。
He was ever the optimist.
他一直是个乐观主义者。
Even when the doctor
said it was cancer,
即使医生
说是癌症，
Billy still insisted he'd be fine.
比利仍然坚持他会没事的。
Time is so fleeting, Mr Herriot.
时间太快了，赫里奥先生。
Any other calls come in?
还有其他电话打进来吗？
Nothing.
没有。
Shame.
耻辱。
I guess we will be taking a day off.
Not so fast.
我想我们会请一天假。
没那么快。
Equipment needs polishing. Done.
设备需要抛光。完毕。
Well, then, the medicines
need topping up. Done.
那么，药物
需要补充。完毕。
All done. Play starts
in five minutes, Mrs H.
全部完成。比赛
在五分钟后开始，H 夫人。
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
What about the...?
等一下。等一下。
怎么样...？
What's wrong with Tristan
enjoying the cricket?
特里斯坦
喜欢板球有什么问题？
He spent all last night
polishing and topping things up.
他昨晚花了一整晚的时间
打磨和补足东西。
There's always more to be done.
总是有更多的事情要做。
Lambing season's almost over.
羔羊季节快结束了。
Summer's our quietest time of year.
夏天是我们一年中最安静的时候。
Surely the lad's earned
a day or two off now.
这小伙子
现在肯定休息了一两天。
Earned?
赚了？
Well, now he's passed
his exams and all.
好吧，现在他已经通过
了考试。
Oh!
哦！
James, I'm so sorry.
I didn't see you there.
詹姆斯，我很抱歉。
我没有在那里看到你。
I've probably had worse flung at me.
我可能遭受了更糟糕的事情。
I wanted to drop in and see
how you were after yesterday.
我想进去看看
你昨天过得怎么样。
Oh, I'm all right, thanks.
哦，我没事，谢谢。
It's Phyllis we're worried about.
我们担心的是菲利斯。
I was just over there now.
我现在刚好在那儿。
Her stirks have got husk.
在这里搅拌已经记住了。
Oh, on top of everything else.
哦，在其他一切之上。
We offered to help
her out with the kids
我们主动提出要帮
她带孩子
but she's determined she can manage.
但她确定她可以应付。
Our Jenny was around the same
age as Billy when my mam died.
我
妈妈去世时，我们的珍妮和比利差不多大。
All the things that family
never got to do together.
家人
从来没有一起做的所有事情。
Now they never will.
现在他们永远不会。
Must have brought back
a lot of painful memories.
一定勾起
了很多痛苦的回忆。
Life's cruel sometimes.
生活有时很残酷。
Be seeing you again soon? I hope so.
很快又要见面了吗？但愿如此。
What are you doing tomorrow night?
明天晚上你在做什么？
Going out with you by the sounds of it.
听着它的声音和你一起出去。
I could pick you up at seven?
我可以七点来接你吗？
I'd like that.
我愿意。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
What on earth?
到底怎么回事？
Tristan, just the man.
特里斯坦，就是那个男人。
Help me carry these out to the barn.
帮我把这些带到谷仓。
What's going on? You'll see.
这是怎么回事？你会看到的。
Now, one cannot be a great vet
现在，一个人不可能成为一名出色的兽医
until one has reared one's own animals.
直到一个人饲养了自己的动物。
Funny, never heard that one before.
Mm-hm.
搞笑，以前没听过。
嗯嗯。
So here you are, Tristan.
所以你来了，特里斯坦。
Meet your new brood.
认识你的新成员。
Wait, what?
等等，什么？
May I suggest you make a start
building a nest box for them?
我可以建议你开始
为他们建造一个巢箱吗？
A nest box? Nothing like
a fresh egg, warm from the nest.
巢箱？没有什么像
新鲜的鸡蛋，从巢中温暖。
Hang on, how come James never
had to rear his own animals?
等等，为什么詹姆斯从来不需要
饲养自己的动物？
This better not be a flock of sheep.
这最好不是一群羊。
Is Uncle Herriot here?
赫里奥叔叔在吗？
No, Uncle...
Mr Herriot is not here, I'm afraid.
不，叔叔……
恐怕赫里奥先生不在。
As I'm sure you're aware,
Mrs Pumphrey is attending
我相信你知道，
Pumphrey 夫人正在参加
the Test match in London and
I am under strict instruction
伦敦的测试赛，
我受到严格的指导
to deposit Tricki Woo into his
guardianship for the duration.
在此期间将 Tricki Woo 存入他的
监护权。
I'm sure Mr Farnon can
provide temporary guardianship
我相信法农先生可以
提供临时监护权
until Uncle Herriot returns.
直到赫里奥叔叔回来。
Most kind.
最亲切。
Now the evening sun sends
long shadows over the gasometers,
现在傍晚的太阳
在煤气表上投下长长的阴影，
Hutton has reached 150
赫顿已达到 150
and, with Leyland by his side,
looks like going on to 1,000.
并且，有了 Leyland 在他身边，
看起来就像是 1,000。
Oh, thought you were Siegfried.
哦，还以为你是齐格弗里德。
Since when do we have hens?
我们什么时候有母鸡了？
Since my big brother decided I need
to rear my own animals.
由于我的大哥决定我需要
饲养自己的动物。
What for? Exactly.
做什么的？确切地。
I thought now that
I'm a fully qualified vet
我想现在
我是一个完全合格的兽医
he'd finally stop hectoring me.
他终于不再威胁我了。
Perhaps he just
doesn't know how to yet.
也许他只是
还不知道该怎么做。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Doesn't seem to matter
what I do, it's never enough.
我做什么似乎无关紧要，这永远不够。
Then why don't you try
standing up to him?
那你为什么不试着
站起来反对他呢？
Worked for me.
为我工作。
You make it sound easy.
你让这听起来很容易。
Perhaps it is.
也许是。
Have you met my brother?
你见过我哥吗？
What is this supposed to be?
这应该是什么？
A nest box?
巢箱？
Give it here.
给这里。
How was your visit to the Dalbys?
您对 Dalbys 的访问如何？
It's not looking good.
看起来不太好。
Oh, dear.
哦亲爱的。
This is Maggie, by the way.
顺便说一下，这是玛吉。
Say hello, Maggie.
打个招呼，玛吉。
And, oh, look, this one here is Brenda.
而且，哦，看，这里的这个是布伦达。
Let me guess - they're all named
after your ex-girlfriends.
让我猜猜——他们都是以
你前女友的名字命名的。
No, not at all.
一点都不。
Here she is.
她在这。
This is Helen,
especially for you, James.
这是海伦，
特别是对你来说，詹姆斯。
Who knows? This one might
even let you take her out.
谁知道？这个
甚至可以让你带她出去。
I'll have you know that Helen and I
我会让你知道海伦和我
are going out on a date tomorrow night.
明天晚上要出去约会。
James!
That's fantastic... Sorry... news!
詹姆士！
太棒了......对不起......消息！
And where are you taking
the lovely Helen?
你要把
可爱的海伦带到哪里去？
Probably just the Drovers.
可能只是 Drovers。
The Drovers?
德罗人？
Look, tomorrow is your big chance
to finally impress Helen.
听着，明天就是你
给海伦留下深刻印象的大好机会。
You should take her to the Renniston.
你应该带她去伦尼斯顿。
Trust me, women like
to be wined and dined.
相信我，女人喜欢
喝酒吃饭。
Seems a bit grand.
好像有点大。
Can't you see it, Jim?
你看不出来吗，吉姆？
The music oozing out of
Benny Thornton's trombone
从
本尼·桑顿的长号中渗出的音乐
and you full of champagne,
and Helen leaning across the table,
你喝着香槟，
海伦斜靠在桌子对面，
the look of love in her eyes.
她眼中的爱意。
Oh, kiss me, Helen.
哦，吻我，海伦。
Oh, OK.
哦好的。
Maybe.
也许。
I mean, after Hugh,
我的意思是，在休之后，
she is probably more used
to the finer things in life.
她可能更习惯于
生活中的美好事物。
You still at it?
你还在吗？
Sorry.
对不起。
I'm still struggling to find
anything that might help Mrs Dalby.
我仍在努力寻找
任何可能对达尔比夫人有帮助的东西。
Don't worry.
别担心。
Here, I'll make a fresh pot.
在这里，我会做一个新鲜的锅。
Oh, Mrs Hall,
do you have a spare stamp?
哦，霍尔太太，
你有备用邮票吗？
Leave it here and I'll post it for you.
把它留在这里，我会为你发布。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
How is your mother?
Still struggling.
你妈妈好吗？
还在挣扎。
I'm just trying to help out
where I can but it's...
我只是想尽
我所能提供帮助，但它...
I'm sure she's grateful
for any help you can manage.
我相信她会感激
你能提供的任何帮助。
It still doesn't feel like it's enough.
还是觉得不够。
To be honest, I just...
老实说，我只是...
I still have no idea
我还是不知道
what I'm supposed to do
about the Glasgow job.
我应该对
格拉斯哥的工作做些什么。
Tricki's finally grown on you, then?
特里奇终于对你长大了，然后？
Like a fungus.
像真菌一样。
Well, he's definitely
taken a shine to you.
嗯，他肯定
对你很有吸引力。
I assure you I've given him
absolutely no reason to.
我向你保证，我
绝对没有给他任何理由。
Could say the same about Tristan.
可以对特里斯坦说同样的话。
He'd follow you
to the ends of the earth.
他会跟着你
到天涯海角。
Only to push me off.
只是为了推开我。
How are Phyllis's stirks
getting on? Not good.
Phyllis 的情绪
如何发展？不好。
It's the worst case of
husk I think I've seen.
这是
我见过的最糟糕的外壳。
Where are you up to?
你到哪里去了？
So we've taken the stirks off the field
所以我们已经把马鞭从球场上拿走了
and I've suggested
a diet of hay and cake. Mm-hm.
我建议
吃干草和蛋糕。嗯嗯。
But without an effective
treatment to speak of,
但没有有效的
治疗可言，
I'm a bit lost as to what else
I can do to try and save them.
对于
我还能做些什么来尝试拯救它们，我有点迷茫。
Perhaps you can't save them.
也许你救不了他们。
Every problem has a solution.
I just need to find it.
每个问题都有解决方案。
我只需要找到它。
I take it you've given them
the throat injection.
我认为你已经给他们
注射了喉咙。
That's just an old farmer's tale.
这只是一个老农民的故事。
Don't say that to their faces.
不要当着他们的面说这些。
I don't want to give her any more
false hope than I already have done.
我不想给她
比我已经做的更多的虚假希望。
And there's not much evidence
to suggest it actually helps.
而且没有太多证据
表明它确实有帮助。
There's not much evidence
that it doesn't help either.
没有太多证据
表明它也没有帮助。
So what have you got to lose?
那你有什么损失？
Morning, all.
Morning. Morning, Tristan.
大家早。
早晨。早上好，特里斯坦。
Fresh eggs coming right up.
新鲜的鸡蛋马上上来了。
We'll make a poulterer of you yet.
我们会让你成为一个保镖。
Good morning, ladies.
早安女士们。
What have you got
for me today, then, hey?
那么，你
今天给我准备了什么，嘿？
They're just getting used
to their new home.
他们只是习惯
了他们的新家。
Poppycock, they're chickens.
罂粟花，它们是鸡。
They don't know their beak
from their feet.
他们
从脚上不知道自己的喙。
It's your job to know what's
best for them. My job - exactly.
知道什么
对他们最好是你的工作。我的工作 - 正是。
And I say they just need a bit of
time and they'll figure it out
我说他们只需要一点
时间 他们就会弄明白
for themselves.
What they need is guidance.
为他们自己。
他们需要的是指导。
Find yourself something resembling
an egg then put it in the nest...
给自己找一个类似
鸡蛋的东西，然后把它放进窝里……
No.
不。
No, what? No, I'm not
listening to you any more.
不，什么？不，我不再
听你的了。
You put me in charge of these hens
so I'm going to do it my way.
你让我负责这些母鸡，
所以我会按照我的方式去做。
You're being ridiculous.
你太可笑了。
And I can guarantee that
by tomorrow morning,
我可以保证到
明天早上，
these hens will have eggs
coming out of their...
这些母鸡会
从它们的...
..ears.
..耳朵。
Wh...
什...
Oh, God damn it,
you stupid bloody animal.
哦，该死的，
你这个愚蠢的血腥动物。
God!
上帝！
Morning, Mrs Dalby.
Hello. How are they today?
早上好，达尔比夫人。
你好。他们今天怎么样？
Still fighting. I've been giving
them the cake and hay like you said.
还在战斗。
就像你说的，我一直在给他们蛋糕和干草。
I emptied my penny jar to pay for cake.
我清空了我的便士罐来买蛋糕。
You're a good lad, Billy.
Your dad would be proud.
你是个好孩子，比利。
你爸爸会很自豪的。
Hey, Billy, give us a hand with this.
嘿，比利，帮我们解决这个问题。
I actually dipped into the family
savings to pay for the cake.
我实际上动用了家庭
储蓄来支付蛋糕。
But Billy was so desperate to help
但是比利非常想帮忙
that I let him think
we used his pennies.
我让他认为
我们用了他的便士。
Probably scatter them on the farm
when he's not looking,
可能
在他不注意的时候把它们撒在农场上，
let him think he's found more.
让他觉得他找到了更多。
What about a throat injection?
Farmers round here swear by it.
喉咙注射怎么办？
这里的农民发誓。
We could try.
我们可以试试。
It's a mix of chloroform,
turpentine and creosote.
它是氯仿、
松节油和杂酚油的混合物。
There's no guarantee that it will
help but... We can always hope.
不能保证它会
有所帮助，但是......我们总是可以希望。
Right, Mr Herriot? Right, aye.
对吧，赫里奥特先生？对，对。
It's nothing serious.
没什么大不了的。
Just a small cut, by the looks of it.
看起来只是一个小切口。
Well, thank God for that.
嗯，为此感谢上帝。
Mrs Pumphrey would
have our guts for garters.
Pumphrey 夫人
对吊袜带有我们的胆量。
That'll teach him to get
involved with the chickens.
那会教他如何
与鸡打交道。
Will it? What?
会吗？什么？
You know very well, what.
你很清楚，什么。
If you'd left well alone,
none of this would have happened.
如果你一个人呆着，
这一切都不会发生。
How is it my fault that he...?
All he wants to do is make you proud
他……怎么是我的错？
他只想让你骄傲
but you set these standards for him
that are impossible to meet.
但是你为他设定了这些
不可能达到的标准。
If you just left him to it once
in a while, maybe he'd surprise you.
如果你只是
偶尔放过他，也许他会让你大吃一惊。
We're not talking about Tricki Woo
any more, are we?
我们不再谈论崔奇雨
了，是吗？
We're simple folk, really, Mr Farnon.
我们是普通人，真的，法农先生。
We all just want the occasional
pat on the head.
我们都只想偶尔
拍拍头。
Isn't that right, Tricki?
不是吗，崔基？
Hm?
嗯？
Mm?
毫米？
Thanks for helping us
with all of this, Mr Herriot.
感谢您帮助我们
解决所有这些问题，Herriot 先生。
Yeah, thank you, Mr Herriot.
好的，谢谢你，赫里奥特先生。
Not at all.
You did all the hard work.
一点也不。
你做了所有的努力。
I had the easy job.
我有一份轻松的工作。
Mr Herriot! Mrs Dalby!
赫里奥特先生！达尔比夫人！
Hey, Billy, why don't you give me
a hand to fetch them some more hay?
嘿，比利，你为什么不帮我
拿些干草给他们呢？
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
I'm not a farmer.
我不是农民。
Billy was the farmer.
比利是农民。
He knew everything there was to know
他知道所有需要知道的
and he was so proud the life we'd
built here and I'm letting him down.
他为我们在
这里建立的生活感到非常自豪，我让他失望了。
Phyllis, you're not
letting anyone down.
菲利斯，你不会
让任何人失望的。
I know it can feel like that sometimes
我知道有时会有这种感觉
but you're doing the best you can.
但你正在尽你所能。
But what if my best isn't good enough?
但是如果我的最好的还不够好怎么办？
What you're trying to do here is hard.
你在这里尝试做的事情很难。
Anyone would doubt themselves.
任何人都会怀疑自己。
Mum, are we going to be all right?
妈妈，我们会没事吗？
Come here, love.
来这里，爱。
Of course we are.
我们当然是。
Here we go, James.
我们走了，詹姆斯。
All fresh and aired.
所有新鲜空气。
Thanks, Mrs H.
谢谢，H太太。
Oh, very handsome.
好帅哦
It'll be a miracle if they
make it through the night.
如果他们
能熬过一夜，那将是一个奇迹。
Having been proved wrong
more than once,
不止一次被证明是错误的
，
I've learned never to underestimate
the resilience of nature.
我学会了永远不要低估
大自然的弹性。
Right, well, I best be off.
好吧，我最好离开。
Cheerio. Good luck.
啦啦队。祝你好运。
Oh...
哦...
Wait a sec.
等一下。
I've posted your letter for you.
Thanks.
我已经把你的信寄给你了。
谢谢。
I know it's hard but you've done
what you can today
我知道这很难，但你
今天已经做了你能做的
for Phyllis and your mother.
为了菲利斯和你妈妈。
Now go have a wonderful time
with Helen. It's important.
现在去
和海伦一起度过美好的时光吧。这一点很重要。
Mr Ingledew. Good evening.
英格杜先生。晚上好。
I presume this is yours.
我想这是你的。
I saw them arrive yesterday.
我昨天看到他们到了。
Tristan?
特里斯坦？
Tristan!
特里斯坦！
Thanks, James.
谢谢，詹姆斯。
Come on, Annabel, let's get you home.
来吧，安娜贝尔，让我们送你回家。
God!
上帝！
That was close.
那很接近了。
Damn it.
该死的。
Oh, no!
不好了！
Damn it.
该死的。
Oh, dear.
哦亲爱的。
You'd better come in, James.
你最好进来，詹姆斯。
Oh, dear, indeed.
哦，亲爱的，确实如此。
The car ran into a bit of
a ditch on the way over.
车子
在路上撞到了一条沟。
Perhaps you can borrow
a pair of my dad's shoes.
也许你可以借
一双我爸爸的鞋子。
Oh, no, that's quite all right.
You can't go out like that.
哦，不，没关系。
你不能就那样出去。
Dad, lend James some shoes
and socks, will you?
爸爸，借给詹姆斯一些鞋子
和袜子，好吗？
There's really no need...
Nonsense. Dad don't mind.
真的没必要……
废话。爸爸不介意。
Here. You can wipe your trousers
down with this. Thanks.
这里。你可以
用这个擦你的裤子。谢谢。
There you go.
你去吧。
My old dancing shoes.
我的旧舞鞋。
Been a while since
they've had an outing.
已经有一段时间，因为
他们已经去春游。
Oh... Honestly, I'll be fine.
哦...老实说，我会没事的。
Are they not to your liking, James?
他们不是你喜欢的吗，詹姆斯？
No, no, these are...
不不不，这些是……
They're perfect.
他们是完美的。
Thank you, Mr Alderson.
谢谢你，奥尔德森先生。
Aye.
是的。
I'll go see what Helen's up to.
我去看看海伦在做什么。
James is here.
詹姆斯来了。
Can you make sure dad checks
the tarpaulin on the barn roof
你能确保爸爸检查
谷仓屋顶的防水油布吗
and make sure...?
Stop worrying. Go enjoy yourself.
并确保...？
别担心了。去享受吧。
Me and Dad will be
just fine without you.
没有你，我和爸爸会过得很好。
Sorry, James.
对不起，詹姆斯。
I thought we could go to the
Renniston for dinner.
我想我们可以去
伦尼斯顿吃晚饭。
I should go and get changed, then.
No, you look...
那我该去换衣服了。
不，你看起来...
..perfect.
..完美的。
Go on, then. Don't want to
be late for the Renniston.
那么继续吧。不想
迟到伦尼斯顿。
I won't be late.
我不会迟到的。
Enjoy yourself, love.
享受自己，爱。
Goodbye.
再见。
I'll get it!
我会得到它的！
Tristan!
特里斯坦！
I give you this simple, little job
one would have thought even you
我给了你一份简单的小工作，
即使是你也会想到
would be hard put to make a mess
of it and look at the situation.
很难把
它弄得一团糟，看看情况。
Not one solitary egg have we seen,
我们没有见过一个单独的鸡蛋，
the bloody hens are flying
about the place like pigeons
血腥的母鸡
像鸽子一样在这个地方飞来飞去
and we are now permanently
estranged from our neighbours.
我们现在
与我们的邻居永久疏远了。
I'm sorry, Siegfried.
I'm sure I put the latch down.
对不起，齐格弗里德。
我确定我把门闩放下了。
I always double-check.
I don't...
我总是仔细检查。
我不...
..want to hear it. Just... try not to
burn the house down while I'm out.
..想听。只是……
我不在的时候尽量不要把房子烧毁。
Who's up for games night?
谁在玩游戏之夜？
Sorry, Mrs Hall, I'm out
with Diana tonight.
抱歉，霍尔夫人，我
今晚要和戴安娜出去。
In fact...
实际上...
..I'm running late as it is.
..我迟到了。
I've got to see a man...
我要见一个人...
..about a chicken.
..关于一只鸡。
Sorry, Mrs H.
对不起，H女士。
Right...
对...
Just me then, is it?
那么只有我，是吗？
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Miss Alderson, how lovely
to see you again. Hello.
奥尔德森小姐，
再次见到你真是太好了。你好。
Would you care for a table, sir?
先生，您需要一张桌子吗？
Yes, please.
是的，请。
Table for two.
两人桌。
This way, please.
这边请。
Excuse me?
打扰一下？
How's Phyllis getting on?
菲利斯最近怎么样？
She lost one of her stirks
when I was there today.
当我今天在那里时，她失去了一根马鞭。
Oh, James, I'm so sorry. That must
have been difficult for you both.
哦，詹姆斯，我很抱歉。这
对你们俩来说一定很困难。
I just wish I'd seen them sooner.
我只是希望我早点见到他们。
She might have had
a fighting chance a week ago.
她可能
在一周前就有了战斗的机会。
Well, you're there now,
嗯，你现在在那里，
and if anyone can pull it off,
it's Phyllis.
如果有人能把它拉下来，
那就是菲利斯。
I just worry it's too little, too late.
我只是担心它太少，太晚了。
It's not like you to give up so easily.
不像你那样轻易放弃。
You didn't see her today.
你今天没看到她。
She's already having to use
her winter supply of hay
她已经不得不
用完冬天的干草了
and spending money that she
doesn't have on expensive cake.
把她
没有的钱花在昂贵的蛋糕上。
I just want to give her
any more false hope.
我只是想给她
更多虚假的希望。
I'm sorry. I shouldn't be
burdening you with all of this.
抱歉。我不应该
让你承受这一切。
You're not burdening me.
你没有给我增加负担。
It's nice that you care.
很高兴你在乎。
Farming's a tough life.
务农生活艰苦。
So much loss and hardship.
这么多的损失和艰辛。
It's bloody hard work.
这是血腥的艰苦工作。
Do you ever think you could leave?
你有没有想过你可以离开？
Do something different? Me?
做点不一样的事？我？
I think about it all the time.
我一直在想它。
I think what it might be like to
not have dirt under my fingernails
我想
我的指甲下没有污垢会是什么感觉
every day, not have to worry
about money, or shovel muck.
每天都不必为
钱发愁，也不必为铲粪发愁。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
I've been thinking
about Phyllis and farming
我一直在考虑
菲利斯和农业
and what you were saying
just now and... and...
还有你
刚才说的……还有……
And what, James?
还有什么，詹姆斯？
Well, perhaps it doesn't
have to be a struggle...
好吧，也许它不必
是一场斗争......
..for Phyllis.
..为了菲利斯。
All the other farmers think
she should sell the farm
所有其他农民都认为
她应该卖掉农场
and maybe they're right.
Maybe it's not too late.
也许他们是对的。
也许现在还不算太晚。
She could sell up, move away,
make a fresh start somewhere new.
她可以卖掉，搬走，
在新的地方重新开始。
All the memories of Billy
are tied up in that farm.
比利的所有记忆
都被绑在那个农场里。
All the boy's memories.
所有男孩的记忆。
That would mean her leaving behind
everything she's ever known.
那将意味着她抛弃了
她所知道的一切。
It's what I had to do.
这是我必须做的。
That's different.
You made a choice to come here.
那不一样。
你做出了来这里的选择。
It doesn't mean it was easy.
这并不意味着这很容易。
My life was in Glasgow,
my friends, my family.
我的生活在格拉斯哥，
我的朋友，我的家人。
It's not the same.
这是不一样的。
Why not?
为什么不？
Because I'm not a farmer?
因为我不是农民？
Because your life isn't
the ground under your feet.
因为你的生活不是
你脚下的土地。
You haven't poured blood, sweat and
tears into the soil you plough.
你还没有把鲜血、汗水和
眼泪倒进你犁过的土壤里。
You haven't raised animals from
birth knowing they could be
你从一
出生就没有养过动物，知道它们可以
taken from your any moment
and, with them, your livelihood.
从您的任何时刻
以及与他们一起夺走您的生计。
I feel like you're making
my argument for me.
我觉得你在为
我辩解。
Billy Dalby took on
that farm from his father,
比利·达尔比
从他父亲那里接手了那个农场，
and his father before him.
It's young Billy's birthright.
和他的父亲在他面前。
这是年轻的比利与生俱来的权利。
So long as there's
something left to inherit.
只要有
东西可以继承。
So you can see yourself
ever leaving, then?
那么你可以看到自己
离开了吗？
Well, I'm not going to
live with my dad forever
好吧，我不会
永远和我爸爸住在一起
but I could never be too far away.
但我永远不会离得太远。
I can't expect you to understand that.
我不能指望你明白这一点。
No.
不。
You're probably right.
你也许是对的。
Is there a spare one of those going?
有空的吗？
Coming right up.
马上就来。
Its not the good stuff I'm afraid,
Siegfried would kill me.
恐怕这不是什么好东西，
齐格弗里德会杀了我。
As long as it's strong and large,
I don't care.
只要它又大又壮，
我不在乎。
Want to talk about it?
想谈谈吗？
Not really.
并不真地。
What have you been up to?
你最近都在做什么？
The usual - disappointing Siegfried,
annoying the neighbours,
惯常的——让齐格弗里德失望，
让邻居们恼火，
creating avian anarchy.
创造鸟类无政府状态。
Siegfried still on your case then?
那么齐格弗里德还在处理你的案子吗？
I think it's his life's work
to be on my case.
我认为
处理我的案子是他毕生的工作。
His magnum opus will be the utter
destruction and destitution
他的代表作将是彻底的
毁灭和贫困
of his little brother.
他的小弟弟。
Did you try standing up to him,
like I suggested?
你有没有
像我建议的那样尝试反抗他？
I did, yes.
我有，是的。
Now it's made everything worse.
现在一切都变得更糟了。
But I've got a plan.
但我有一个计划。
Won't it feel like a shallow victory?
不会感觉像是一场肤浅的胜利吗？
A victory is a victory nonetheless.
总之胜利就是胜利。
Hello.
你好。
Look at that!
看那个！
He's only gone and bloody done it.
他只是走了而且该死的做到了。
The taste of a fresh egg,
can't beat it.
新鲜鸡蛋的味道，
无法打败它。
Are you heading up to
the Dalby's today?
你
今天要去 Dalby's 吗？
Unfortunately, yes.
不幸的是，是的。
I have no idea what to say to the
poor woman. I could see the look
我不知道该对这个
可怜的女人说什么。我可以看到外观
of hope on her face when I gave
the stirks the throat injection.
当我给
马镫喉咙注射时，她的脸上充满了希望。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I just don't feel like I'm
being honest.
我只是觉得我
不诚实。
Honesty is the best policy.
诚实是最好的政策。
Of course, the throat injection
was never going to work.
当然，喉咙注射
永远不会奏效。
What?
什么？
But you were the one that told me
to give it to them.
但你是那个告诉我
把它给他们的人。
This isn't about the injection.
这与注射无关。
Look, it's the worst part of the job
看，这是工作中最糟糕的部分
when you realise everything
is in the lap of the gods.
当你意识到一切
都在众神的怀抱中。
But at least now you can
look Phyllis in the eye and tell her
但至少现在你可以
看着菲利斯的眼睛告诉她
you have tried absolutely everything.
你已经尝试了一切。
And as long as you've tried everything,
只要你尝试了一切，
then you've done your job.
那么你就完成了你的工作。
You'll find the right thing to say,
I have no doubt.
你会找到正确的说法，
我毫不怀疑。
Thanks, Siegfried.
谢谢，齐格弗里德。
I know that I can set these high
standards at times,
我知道我
有时可以设定这些高标准，
and perhaps come across
as slightly overbearing...
也许会
让人觉得有点霸道......
Slightly.
轻微地。
It's only because I want
the best for you both.
只是因为我想
给你们俩最好的。
And, Tristan, maybe I should
trust you a bit more.
而且，特里斯坦，也许我应该多
信任你一点。
And...
和...
..recognise your successes
when you have them.
..
当你拥有成功时就承认你的成功。
It's a week's wage.
这是一周的工资。
Well done.
做得好。
You were right about the hens
你对母鸡的看法是对的
and you've more than proved
yourself of late.
而且你最近证明了
自己。
Thanks, Siegfried.
谢谢，齐格弗里德。
You've earned it.
这是你应得的。
Actually, I've got
a confession to make.
事实上，我有
一个忏悔。
I think I'd better get going.
我想我最好走。
Confession?
告白？
It's just, I wanted
so desperately to make you proud
只是，我
拼命想让你骄傲
and do something right for
a change and...
并为
改变做一些正确的事情......
..I lied.
..我撒了谎。
I bought the eggs from the grocers
and planted them
我从杂货店买了鸡蛋
然后种了
in the nest box last night.
昨晚在巢箱里。
Here.
这里。
Right...
对...
Take it.
拿着。
We all make mistakes.
我们都会犯错。
The thing is to forgive and...
事情是原谅和...
..learn from them.
..向他们学习。
What mistakes?
什么错误？
Well, it might have been me
that left the barn door open.
好吧，可能是我
把谷仓的门打开了。
In my defence, Tricky had just
been attacked and...
在我的辩护中，Tricky 刚刚
遭到袭击并且……
I suppose that makes us even,
doesn't it?
我想这会让我们变得平等，
不是吗？
Does it?
I'd take it if I were you.
可以？
如果我是你，我会接受。
I'll get it.
我会得到它的。
Thanks, Siegfried.
谢谢，齐格弗里德。
I see you've lost another one.
我看你又丢了一个。
We have.
我们有。
But Mrs Dalby's sure she noticed an
improvement in the others' appetite.
但多尔比夫人确信她注意到
其他人的胃口有所改善。
That must be a good sign.
这一定是个好兆头。
Let's go have a look at them, shall we?
我们去看看他们好吗？
How are they looking, Mr Herriot?
他们看起来怎么样，赫里奥特先生？
I wish I had some better news,
but they're still very sick.
我希望我有一些更好的消息，
但他们仍然病得很重。
Now, I know you've told me
not to turn the young beasts
现在，我知道你告诉过我
不要让这些年轻的野兽
out onto the field any more,
but isn't there a way around it?
不再进入球场，
但没有办法绕过它吗？
Perhaps it could help to get them
back outside.
也许这有助于让他们
回到外面。
No, I'm sorry.
不，我很抱歉。
Until there's a vaccine,
there's no way of safeguarding them
在没有疫苗之前，
没有办法保护它们
against husk.
对壳。
Then we will just have to find
another solution.
然后我们只需要找到
另一个解决方案。
I...
一世...
Mrs Dalby,
达尔比夫人，
this is what I've been meaning to
talk to you about.
这就是我一直想
和你谈的。
I've been giving the matter a great
deal of thought and, well,
我一直在考虑这个问题
，嗯，
you've lost so much already...
你已经失去了很多...
I just couldn't live with myself if
I didn't give you my honest opinion.
如果
我不给你我诚实的意见，我就无法忍受自己。
I see.
我知道了。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
I really am, but we've tried
everything now, and there's still
我真的是，但我们
现在已经尝试了一切，仍然有
a very real chance you could end up
losing the entire herd.
一个非常真实的机会，你最终可能会
失去整个牛群。
So there's a chance that we
might not then?
那么我们有
可能不会吗？
A slim one, yes.
一个苗条的，是的。
I've given you so much
false hope already.
我已经给了你太多
虚假的希望。
I really think that now your best
course of action is to sell
我真的认为现在你最好
的做法是出售
the farm before it's too late.
在为时已晚之前的农场。
There's nothing false about hope,
Mr Herriot.
希望并没有什么虚假，
赫里奥特先生。
Yes, but...
I appreciate your honesty, I do.
是的，但是……
我很欣赏你的诚实，我很欣赏。
But I've been giving it a great
deal of thought too,
但我也
想了很多，
and I understand the risk involved.
我了解所涉及的风险。
But, when I look around...
但是，当我环顾四周时...
..I don't just see the things
I've lost or might lose,
..我不只是看到
我已经失去或可能失去的东西，
I see everything I have.
我看到了我所拥有的一切。
I see my boys.
我看到了我的孩子们。
How I have so much
worth fighting for still.
我怎么还有那么多
值得为之奋斗的东西。
And I owe it to them,
to my family, not to give up.
我欠他们，欠
我的家人，不要放弃。
Even if it is the slimmest
of chances, I'll take it.
哪怕是最渺茫
的机会，我也要把握住。
I might not have been able to
save my husband, Mr Herriot,
我可能
救不了我的丈夫 Herriot 先生
but I can save our farm.
但我可以拯救我们的农场。
Our home.
我们的家。
So we're staying put.
所以我们要原地踏步。
Like my Billy always used to say,
就像我的比利常说的那样，
only them as has them can lose them.
只有拥有它们的人才能失去它们。
Now, come on,
you must have one of these scones,
现在，来吧，
你必须有这些烤饼之一，
they're fresh from the oven.
它们是刚出炉的。
That's it, that's the record.
就是这样，这就是记录。
He's done it!
他做到了！
Brilliant, brilliant.
辉煌，辉煌。
Wonderful.
精彩的。
I'll get it.
我会得到它的。
Tricky, Mummy's here.
棘手，妈妈来了。
Darling, dearest boy,
how have you been?
亲爱的，最亲爱的孩子，
你好吗？
Mrs Pumphrey, do come in.
Pumphrey 夫人，请进。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Forgive my early arrival,
原谅我早到，
our separation became far too
unbearable.
我们的分离变得太
难以忍受了。
Quite all right.
I'll fetch some tea.
完全没问题。
我去拿点茶。
Do sit down, Mrs Pumphrey.
Allow me.
坐下来，Pumphrey 夫人。
允许我。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
I so appreciate his Uncle Herriot
looking after him so well.
我非常感谢他的赫里奥特叔叔
把他照顾得这么好。
Where is our dear James?
我们亲爱的詹姆斯在哪里？
Out on a call, I'm afraid.
恐怕要出去接电话了。
Oh, what a pity.
噢真可惜。
How was your trip?
你的旅途怎么样？
Hutton and Leyland made quite the pair.
Hutton 和 Leyland 是一对。
I almost dropped my binoculars
in all the excitement.
我
兴奋得差点丢掉双筒望远镜。
We just heard,
Hutton beat Bradman's record.
我们刚刚听说，
赫顿打破了布拉德曼的记录。
Terrific!
了不起！
Which reminds me, I do hope you are
practising your inswinger,
这让我想起了，我确实希望你正在
练习你的浪荡公子，
ready for
my little cricket match this summer.
准备好参加
今年夏天的小板球比赛。
Of course, wouldn't miss it for the
world, Mrs Pumphrey.
当然，
全世界都不会错过的，Pumphrey 夫人。
Wonderful.
精彩的。
Look, Tricky, your favourite.
看，Tricky，你最喜欢的。
He does love a home-made biscuit.
他确实喜欢自制饼干。
They're actually for you, Mrs Pumphrey.
他们实际上是给你的，Pumphrey 夫人。
Oh, I only eat a Fortnum myself.
哦，我自己只吃一个Fortnum。
But Tricky is a little less fussy.
但 Tricky 就不那么挑剔了。
And how was my darling boy been?
我亲爱的男孩过得怎么样？
I do hope he has behaved himself.
我确实希望他表现得很好。
Well...
好...
Honesty...
诚实...
Yes, um...
是的，嗯...
Truth be told, there was
a slight incident.
说实话，发生
了一件小事。
I took temporary charge
of Tricky while James...
我临时负责
Tricky，而 James...
While Uncle Herriot was on a call,
当赫里奥特叔叔打电话时，
turned my back for a second
转过我一秒
and Tricky did receive a tiny
peck from one of our hens.
Tricky 确实
从我们的一只母鸡那里得到了一点点啄。
I take full responsibility,
I'm terribly sorry.
我承担全部责任，
非常抱歉。
Tricky always goes
completely cracker-dog
Tricky 总是
完全变态
when there's a chicken in sight.
当看到一只鸡时。
Tricky woo-lally I call it.
棘手的 woo-lally 我称之为。
I couldn't tell you what
he has against them
我无法告诉你
他对他们有什么不满
but that will be the fifth peck
he has had this year.
但这将是
他今年的第五次啄食。
Oh, right.
啊对。
Perhaps it's because he's an only dog.
也许是因为他是唯一的狗。
I do think that an only
develops more prejudices
我确实认为只会
产生更多的偏见
than one from a large family.
比一个来自大家庭的人。
Wouldn't you agree?
你不同意吗？
Try not to be upset.
尽量不要生气。
You will see your uncles
again very soon.
你
很快就会再次见到你的叔叔。
And the pain of parting is
nothing to the joy of meeting again.
而离别之痛，
与重逢之乐无关。
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Good day, Mrs Pumphrey.
美好的一天，庞弗里夫人。
Goodbye, Tricky.
再见，崔克。
Oh, of course, Tricky, yes,
where are my manners?
哦，当然，Tricky，是的，
我的礼貌在哪里？
Francois, would you mind?
弗朗索瓦，你介意吗？
You reminded me...
你提醒我...
To say thank you.
要说谢谢。
Oh.
哦。
To his Uncle Herriot.
给他的赫里奥特叔叔。
The kippers - exquisite.
腌鱼 - 精致。
Right, home, please, Francois.
好的，请回家，弗朗索瓦。
Toodle-oo.
嘟嘟哦。
Bye-bye.
再见。
Come on!
来吧！
Phyllis lost another stirk.
菲利斯又失去了一根鞭子。
A few more are on their way out.
还有一些正在离开。
But she is determined to keep going,
但她决心继续前进，
even if it's only with half a herd.
即使只有半群。
You were right.
你是对的。
I get it now, and I'm sorry about...
我现在明白了，我很抱歉...
This was my mum's favourite spot
up here on this roof.
这是我妈妈
在这个屋顶上最喜欢的地方。
Used to come up here at lunchtime
and eat our sandwiches.
过去常常在午餐时间来这里
吃我们的三明治。
She'd point out different
parts of the farm and tell me,
她会指出
农场的不同部分并告诉我，
"That's where you scraped your knee
trying to jump over the bales."
“这就是你
试图跳过大包时擦伤膝盖的地方。”
"That's where you helped out
with your first lambing."
“那是你帮助
你第一次产羔的地方。”
"And that spot there..."
“还有那个地方……”
"..that's where I told your dad
I were pregnant with you."
“……那是我告诉你爸爸
我怀了你的地方。”
"And his grin filled
his whole face."
“他的笑容充满
了他的整张脸。”
Subtitles by Red Bee Media
Red Bee Media 字幕